翻譯:Dusty 校對:Dusty 潤色: Dusty
聯繫方式QQ174898201
沒有幾個人知道完整的故事經過
Few know the whole story.
就我回憶 其實是這樣的...
From what I recall, it goes something like this...
在故事開始之前
Before history began,
埃及是世界萬物的誕生地
Egypt was the birthplace of all life.
由眾神創造的天選之國
A paradise worthy of the gods who created it.
所以眾神選擇居住在這
So the gods decided to live there
與他們創造的劣等生物一起生活
alongside their lesser creation,
人類
man.
雖然居住在一起
But there was no mistaking the gods
但是人類敬拜著眾神們
amongst the mortals who worshipped them.
眾神更加高大
The gods were taller
身體堿y淌著黃金 而不是血液
with gold running through their veins instead of blood.
而且他們能隨時隨地
And they could transform at will
變身成各種駭人的野獸
into all manner of frightening beasts.
而埃及被一對兄弟一分為二分開統治
Egypt itself was divided between two mighty brothers.
奧西奡 豐饒神 被人民愛戴
Osiris, the god of life, was the beloved king
統治著尼羅河周邊的富饒土地
of all the lands made bountiful by the nile.
他弟弟 賽特(荒漠神) 則統治著寸草不生的荒漠
His brother, set, ruled the far barren desert
暗地堣@直儲備力量 憎恨著他哥哥
finding both strength and bitterness in his isolation.
後來奧西奡絲Ёぁ[冕新王
But then the time came for osiris to crown a new king.
也就是他唯一的兒子 荷魯斯(天空神)
His only son, horus.
這個決定考驗了兄弟的團結
It was a decision that would test the brothers' bond
也影響了全埃及的命運
and the fate of all Egypt.
但是這故事堨u有一半是關於眾神的
But the gods are only half our tale.
眾所周知
It had become clear
眾神無法僅靠自身之力就決定世界的命運
that they couldn't shape the course of destiny alone.
還需要一個 判斷力
A man of exceptional judgment,
智慧 以及勇氣都過人的男人
wisdom and fortitude would be needed.
很不幸 我不是這麼優秀的人
Unfortunately, I was not such a man.
在你們批評年輕的我之前
But before you dismiss my younger foolhardy self,
請記住...
remember...
千萬不要低估
Never doubt a man
一個為了追求 和眾神一般強大的東西 奮鬥的男人
fighting for the one thing as powerful as any god.
三百 太貴了
Three hundred, impossible.
愛情
Love.
這是市場最低價了
It's the best price.
小偷 !
Thief!
站住 !
Stop!
這裙子太難看了
This dress is hopeless.
想要參加明天的加冕禮
I need to buy some ribbon to even begin
還得買些緞帶才行
to make it suitable for the coronation.
那我們明天一起過吧
I say we spend tomorrow together instead.
我們明天本來就是一起過 一起去參加加冕禮
We are spending tomorrow together. At the coronation.
仁慈的上帝會賜予我們
We're blessed the gods shall give us
一位新國王
a new king in our lifetime.
荷魯斯 ?
Horus?
你明白我根本不在乎眾神的
You know I couldn't care less about the gods.
可他們在乎你
Well, they care about you.
- 是嗎 ?  - 快還給我
Oh, yeah? Bek! Give it back.
我知道你希望穿漂亮的裙子
I knew you wanted to wear something special.
這是你從商店偷的
Did you steal it from a shopkeeper
還是從別人衣櫃堸蔽 ?
or from someone's closet?
總比等待眾神回應我的祈禱
It was quicker than waiting for the gods
快多了
to answer my prayers.
眾神給予了我們一切
The gods give us everything we need.
是的 他們無限慷慨
Yes. Their generosity knows no bounds.
你真漂亮
You look beautiful.
薩亞 我當時叫你和我私奔的時候
Zaya, when I asked you to run away with me,
我給你承諾過舒適的生活
I promised you a good life.
還會送你很多華貴的裙子
Dresses worthy of a Princess.
每天都送新的
A new one every day.
用無數珠寶來襯托你
Rivers of jewels to adorn you.
還能住在黃金皇宮養育家庭
A golden palace to raise our family.
那我們會有多少孩子 ?
And how many children would we have?
十多個
A dozen.
我願意做任何事換你開心
I would do anything to make you happy.
而荷魯斯 即將上任的國王
And how was horus, the king-to-be,
是怎麼為加冕禮做準備的呢 ?
preparing for his great day?
天空神
Lord of the air.
昨晚又忙活了吧
Quite an occasion last night.
人們都已經聚集過來了
Already crowds press cheek-to-cheek
都是來看看您風采的
to catch a glimpse of you.
您會非常莊嚴輝煌
You will look splendid.
就現在這樣可不行
Eventually.
但也別就這樣低估荷魯斯了
But don't discount horus yet either.
當要決定世界命運
Because when it comes to the fate of the world
的時刻
in one's hands,
就算是眾神 也會被自身的力量所震撼
even gods can be surprised by the strength they possess.
如果是我要當國王的話
If I was to be crowned,
我會在儀式前抽點時間
I might have spent the preceding hours
準備好演講稿
composing a message for my people.
難道人們還能更愛他嗎 ?
Could the people love him more?
或許荷魯斯大人覺得不用搞那些陳詞爛調
Maybe lord horus doesn't think we need boring speeches.
事關自己的榮耀就得準備
Except when it comes to toasting his own glory.
我都為人們做得夠多了
Many toasts were required.
我的所作所為都被書寫成詩歌了
I was doing deeds of which songs will be sung.
他當初殺死的那隻大獅子的確破壞了很多村莊
The great lion he slayed was terrorizing villages.
是嗎 ? 太好了 又一個詩歌材料
It was? Good. All the more song-worthy.
真舒服
That's nice.
不用了 謝謝...
That's fine, thank...
是你
You.
真遺憾我遲到了
A shame I've come too late.
不過我還是來了 又清醒又穿了衣服
But here I am, sober and clothed.
別告訴別人
Don't tell anyone.
我還得維持名聲呢
I have a bad reputation to keep.
過來
Come here. Come.
不不不 !
No. No, no. No, no!
不敢相信 你穿這身衣服還真有模有樣的
Hard to believe, but you look like a king.
如果這樣你就興奮了 我也不好說什麼
If that's what excites you, who am I to judge?
珠寶能讓我興奮
Jewelry excites me.
那看看你自己的手腕
Then look to your wrist,
如果你不嫌太華麗的話
if the effort is not too great.
42星手鐲
The bracelet of 42 stars.
別忘記當初我為了你殺的那些惡魔
To remind you of the demons I slayed for you.
埃及從沒見過的貴重寶物
A more valuable treasure Egypt has never known.
就這老玩意 ?
This old thing?
為什麼愛神卻不明白愛是什麼東西 ?
How can the goddess of love not know what love is?
到處睡女人可不算愛
It's not bedding any girl who flutters her eyelashes,
勇猛的巨獅獵手
mighty lion-slayer.
我當時只是在慶祝而已
I was celebrating the hunt.
如果你在現場你就明白了
You would know that had you been here.
我看重自己的自由 不怎麼看重動物屍體
I value my freedom. Dead animals less so.
可你把它們穿在身上卻沒什麼意見
Well, you have no problem wearing them.
- 噢  - 哈索爾(愛神) 別
Oh... Hathor, don't.
別
Don't.
這可不是王后該有的樣子
That's no way for a queen to behave.
那還好我不是女王
Then it's a good thing I'm not a queen.
你能想出比整天坐在王座上
Can you imagine anything more dull than sitting
更無聊的事嗎 ?
on a throne all day?
你到底是想問我什麼 ?
What exactly are you asking me?
我有問你什麼事嗎 ?
Did I ask you something?
我不確定 你說啊
I'm not sure. Did you?
大人
My lord.
儀式開始了
It's starting.
哈索爾 愛神 !
Hathor, goddess of love!
奈芙蒂斯 守護神 !
Nephthys, goddess of protection!
- 先生  - 噢...
Sir. Oh...
謝謝你 小伙子
Thank you, young man.
你今天對陌生人怎麼這麼友善
You've been awfully nice to strangers today.
把手伸出來
Show me your hands.
幹嘛 ? 這是送給奧西奡答甄妒
What? Gifts for osiris.
快走吧
Hurry up!
托特 睿智神 !
Thoth, god of wisdom!
你好 托特
Greetings, thoth.
你沒有想到自己的學生
Did you ever imagine that your former student
某天居然當上國王了吧 ?
would one day wear the crown of Egypt?
荷魯斯的人格
Horus evinced a range of attributes,
和領袖位置有很強的契合度
some of which may well correlate with a leadership position.
如果他夠幸運的話
If he's lucky.
讚美奧西奡 !
Praise osiris!
全埃及之王 !
King of all Egypt!
拉主神 光之主萬歲 (Ra 主神/太陽神)
Hail ra, lord of light.
Hail ra, lord of light!
我父親祝福著今日
My father has seen fit to bless this day
就如你們用慷慨祝福我們一樣
as you all bless us with your generosity.
這是一個富人的禮物
A token from someone with much.
而這是一個窮人的禮物
And from someone with little.
但當他們最終站在來世之門面前
But when both die and stand at the final gate,
到時候這禮物有多少價值 ?
what is their value then?
要我說價值是平等的
I say they are equal.
都是他們好好活過的證明
Symbols of lives well-lived.
來世歡迎所有人
All are welcome to the afterlife.
這是我的遺產
This is my legacy.
但今天 我們要為新國王加冕
But today, we crown a new king.
而以後某日 他也會擁有自己的遺產
And one day, he will have a legacy of his own.
我的兒子荷魯斯 天空神
My son horus, lord of the air.
準備好了沒 ?
Are you ready?
好了
I am.
等等
Wait!
Wait.
抱歉來遲了
Sorry I'm late.
額 穿越沙漠花了3天
Ugh, three days to cross the desert.
而穿過你的信徒們也差點花了1天
And nearly one more to pass through all your admirers.
賽特
Set!
哥哥 真高興見到你
Brother. Good to see you.
我也是 弟弟
And you, brother.
這堛漱j門永遠向你敞開
There's always a place for you here.
今天對家族來說是個大日子 你肯定很驕傲
Such a big day for the family. You must be proud.
確實
I am.
瞧瞧你啊 侄子 真是華麗
Look at you, nephew. Magnificent.
至少這堨H後還是有個好國王的
At least someone here'll make a fine king.
我怕你不來了呢
I was afraid you wouldn't come.
不 我絕不會錯過的
No, I wouldn't miss it.
啊
Ah.
- 給你的  - 噢...
For you. Oh...
獵號
A hunting horn.
這只巨羊在遇上我之前打敗了10位神
From the skull of a ram that flattened 10 gods slower than me.
真精美
It's beautiful.
是嗎 ?  試試吧
Yeah? Try it out.
賽特送的
From set.
來吧 讓主神聽聽你的呼喊吧
Come on! Let ra himself hear you.
看來的確有人聽到了
I think someone heard you.
你這是什麼意思 賽特 ?
What is this, set?
認出來了嗎 ?
You recognize it?
這是父親給你的
Father gave it to you.
在沙漠夜晚保護了我很多次
Kept me alive for many a night in the desert.
和我打一場
Fight me.
- 父親 別  - 你別管 兒子
Father, don't. Stay out of this, son.
為什麼 ?
Why?
和平了1000年 你又完成了什麼事業 ?
In 1,000 years of peace, what have you accomplished?
一群毫無夢想的人
A land of people who dream of nothing more.
該我當國王了
It's my turn now.
我不會和你戰鬥的
I won't fight.
我愛你 弟弟 打心底媟R著
I love you, brother. With all my heart.
不 !
No!
我也愛你 哥哥
I love you, too, brother.
不 !
No!
奧西奡 !
Osiris!
看來今天確實是家族的大日子
Well, this truly is a big day for the family.
我 斯特
I, set,
將成為你們真正的國王
shall be your one true king.
全埃及之王 !
King of all Egypt!
這就是阻擾我的下場
Behold the fate of those who stand in my way.
眾神們...
Gods...
臣服於我 否則去死
Bow before me or die.
凡人們 敬拜我 否則就當奴隸 !
Mortals, worship me or be enslaved!
貝克
Bek!
我哥哥認為來世是一份禮物
My brother thought the afterlife was a gift.
而我覺得作為國王應該更有追求才對
I think a king should have higher standards.
從現在起 想進入來世
From now on, you have to buy your way in
必須交貢
with riches earned.
你的旅程才剛剛開始
Your journey has just begun.
送給你了
It's yours now.
我們很多人會支援你 但現在不是戰鬥的時候
Many of us will stand with you, but now is not the time.
- 我曾經很敬仰你  - 廢話
I looked up to you. Of course you did.
你這樣就太愚蠢了
That would be unwise.
聽說你從不失手 ?
Is it true you still never miss?
難道你不覺得無聊麼 ?
Doesn't that get dull?
不是說你擁有完美的視力麼
I thought your sight was perfect.
你打得不錯
You fight well.
你確定你是他親兒子 ?
Are you so sure you're his son?
薩亞 !
Zaya!
- 貝克  - 薩亞 !
Bek! Zaya!
貝克 !
Bek!
我這是為埃及好 你不適合當國王
I'm doing Egypt a favor. You're not fit to be king.
不 !
No!
賽特 !
Set!
原諒我 父親
Forgive me, father.
薩亞 !
Zaya!
賽特當上了國王
And so set was king.
多年來 很多神明們都反抗過他
In the year that followed, many gods stood against him.
一個接一個 都付出了生命的代價
One by one, they paid with their lives.
至於凡人 情況更加不幸
For mortals, things were worse.
大部分人都被強迫成了奴隸
Most were forced into slavery,
而根本不給工錢
and denied even the tiniest penny
買不起貢品進入來世
to buy our way into the afterlife.
被打敗後挖出雙眼 荷魯斯被放逐出境
Blinded and defeated, horus withdrew into exile.
那些祈禱他回來拯救埃及的人
Those who prayed for him to save Egypt
只迎來了失望
were sorely disappointed.
但我從來不怎麼喜歡祈禱
But I was never much for prayer.
我發現薩亞被賣給了一個暴主
I had found zaya enslaved to a cruel master.
但我怎麼拯救她呢 ?
But how could I free her from all this?
這是我最瘋狂的計劃
It was the maddest of all plans.
你或許控制不了風 薩亞
You may not control the wind, zaya,
但我覺得你還是能把窗戶關上的
but I'd think you could close a shutter.
抱歉 大人
Sorry, my lord.
漂亮小妞 如果我的桌子再這麼凌亂
Pretty one, if ever I find my desk disordered again,
我就派你出去推石頭
I'll throw you outside to push stone.
明白沒 ?
Is that clear?
快走 我時間可不多
Come on, come on! Haven't got all day.
我真想把他從高處推下去
I'd like to drop him from a great height.
早安
Morning.
總有一日 我會把你從他身邊偷走
One day, I'm going to steal you away from him.
難道你只會玩偷竊行徑嗎 ?
Is theft always the answer?
現在這個世界只能靠偷了 要麼富有 要麼豬狗不如
It is now in this world. You're either rich or nothing.
就算你能救我出去
Even if you could free me,
那我家人怎麼辦 ? 還有我們的朋友
what about my family? Our friends?
你能從賽特手中偷走整個埃及嗎 ?
Can you steal all Egypt away from set?
只有荷魯斯能拯救我們
Only horus can free us.
你真覺得眾神們在乎嗎 ?
You really believe the gods care?
如果荷魯斯能回來 他就在乎
If horus could come, he would.
我想讓你看點東西
I want to show you something.
賽特的軍隊帶著戰利品回來了
Set's army returns with spoils of war.
他的寶庫今晚會開啟
His vault will be unlocked tonight.
這是一個
The perfect time
潛入的完美時機
for someone to sneak inside.
為什麼 ?
Why?
人們說荷魯斯的眼睛被保管在堶
They say horus' eyes are kept there.
有了眼睛就能找回力量
He would have his power again.
從神手中偷東西 ?
Steal from a god?
只有瘋子才會這樣做
Only a madman would try such a thing.
那你覺得我們上哪去找這樣一個瘋子 ?
Where do you suppose we could find someone so mad?
圖紙應該就在這
The plans should be here.
寶庫是烏許建的 他是賽特的建築師
Urshu built the vault. He's set's architect.
這是啥 ?
What's this?
賽特的沙築金字塔
Uh, set's pyramid of sand.
他還建造了個巨大的火山坑
He's built himself quite the fire pit.
他肯定烤過很多山珍佳餚
He must cook massive feasts.
那火山坑是通往世界的中心的
It's the pit to the center of the world.
那堿O他力量的來源 不是用來烤肉的
The source of his power. No feasts.
找到了
Found it.
寶物會從前門通過
The treasure will pass through the front gate.
前門不是什麼問題
The front gate isn't the problem.
接下來才是
It's what comes after.
兩座充滿陷阱的大橋
Two Bridges rigged with traps.
烏許還經常以此自誇
Urshu boasts of them endlessly.
好在我擅長作弊
Good thing I'm cheating.
要拜訪我就好好拜訪 士兵
Welcome me properly, soldier.
別讓埃及女王等久了
Don't keep the queen of Egypt waiting.
我覺得你想我了
I think you missed me.
我必須想你才行
I have to miss you.
我畢竟是你的俘虜
I'm your prisoner, after all.
那這座監獄還不賴嘛
Oh, this prison's not so bad.
可我很不開心
Well, I'm miserable.
你都是這樣表達不開心的嗎
You have a funny way of showing it.
我能借用你的刀嗎 ?
Can I borrow your knife?
好讓你有機會殺了我 ?
So if you had the chance, you'd kill me?
我怎麼殺得了你 ?
How could I kill you?
但你有機會就會下手
But you would if you could.
那你最好堤防下我了
Better keep your eyes open.
賽特大人
Lord set.
噢...
Oh...
以及... 女士
And, uh... mistress.
或許我該另找時間拜訪
Perhaps I might come at a better time.
不用 進來吧 別害羞
No, come in. Don't be shy.
過來吧
Come on.
從沒有人為拉主神建造過這樣巨大的雕像
No one has ever so honored the great god ra.
他的神跡將會流芳百代
He will pass over its peak and marvel
以及您為他做出的貢獻
at the tribute you have built in his name.
僅此而已 ?
Is that it?
抱歉 ?
I'm sorry?
能建得更高點麼 ?
Well, can you make it any taller?
更高 ?
Taller?
沒錯 這問題很簡單的
Yes, it's a simple question.
額 有可能會有點困難
Well, that might be difficult, um,
我指的是...
now, I mean...
放鬆點 烏許 我開玩笑的
Relax, urshu. I'm joking.
告訴我
Tell me,
為什麼你父親選擇你來當主建築師
why'd your father choose you to be master builder
而不是你那幾個兄弟 ?
rather than one of your brothers?
我估計應該是我證明了自己是最優秀的 大人
I suppose because I proved to be the best, my lord.
就如同我也會證明我是父親最優秀的兒子
As I shall prove to be the best to my father.
他將見證我為他做的一切
He shall see it from dawn to dusk.
您的滿意比金子更重要
Your satisfaction is worth more than gold.
金子 金子
Oh, gold, gold!
你進入來世之後肯定有著花不完的金子
You'll have plenty enough gold for the afterlife.
乾杯 !
A toast!
敬埃及最優秀的建築師
To Egypt's greatest builder.
敬我的遺產
A toast to my legacy.
喔 !
Whoa!
你上哪找的這麼多蝎子啊 ?
Where do you even get that many scorpions?
看來得小心自己的影子了
Enough to make you afraid of your own shadow.
"圓環是機關"
"The circle is the trigger."
那我就繞開走
So I'll go 'round.
還挺簡單的
Well, that was easy.
第三座橋
A third bridge.
上面可沒寫什麼第三座橋啊
Doesn't say anything about a third bridge.
簡直作弊
This is criminal.
而且只有一隻眼
And only one eye.
這下好了
Terrific.
薩亞 為我祈禱吧
Zaya, you'd say a prayer, I'll roll the bones.
薩亞 !
Zaya!
真對不起
I'm so sorry.
用我的房子來通姦還不夠是嗎...
As if using my house for your fornicating were not sufficient...
你居然敢偷國王的東西
You dare steal from the king?
我希望自己的辦公室調理有序 薩亞
I pride myself in an orderly office, zaya.
可你從不明白這一點 對吧 ?
You never did understand that, did you?
還有你這可悲的小掛件
Oh, and this pathetic little trinket of yours
恐怕救你們內中一人都不夠
will save neither of you, I'm afraid.
賽特是你的神明
Set is your god.
- 這都是我的主意  - 騙子 !
It was all my idea. Liar!
把你偷的東西交出來
Give me back what you took.
謝謝
Thank you.
- 把他們拉出去餵財狼  - 等等 !
Feed them to the jackals. Wait!
我還拿了另外的東西
I took something else.
快跑 !
Run!
- 你成功了  - 另一隻在哪 ?
You did it. Where's the other?
你知道偷一隻有多難嗎 ?
You know how hard it was to steal that one?
我會永遠愛你
I'll love you forever.
薩亞
Zaya.
死亡並不是終結
Death is not the end.
薩亞
Zaya.
喔
Whoa.
我會救你的 薩亞
I'll make it right, zaya.
我不需要信徒
I don't need any more worshippers.
也不需要你們惡臭的貢品
Tributes that rot and stink.
除非你有酒 否則滾出去
Unless you brought more wine, get out.
我不是信徒
I'm no worshipper.
那你是什麼 ? 小偷 ?
What are you? Some thief?
沒錯 小偷
Yes. A thief.
我手上有賽特從你那奪走的東西
I have something set took from you.
沒有凡人能盜竊賽特的寶庫
No mortal could rob set's vault.
這是你殺害我的信徒搶去的
You pilfered one of my followers' corpses.
他們根本沒發現我
They never even got close.
交出來
Give them to me.
還不行
Not yet.
把雙眼還給我
Give me my eyes.
我有項提議
I have a proposition.
你居然敢和我討價還價 ?
You bargain with me?
你很幸運 我願意和你討價
You're lucky I'm willing to.
就你這樣子連大象都打不到
You can't strike a three-legged elephant.
你是想要回報吧 ? 金子 ?
You want a reward, I suppose? Gold?
我自己能偷金子
Gold I can steal.
有個我想救的人 ?
There's someone I want saved.
從哪救 ?
From what?
死亡
Death.
你父親不是教過你死亡不是終結嗎 ?
Didn't your father teach that death isn't the end?
這是不可能的
It can't be done.
那你想辦法啊 你可是荷魯斯 天空之神
Well, figure it out. You're horus, lord of the air!
要不然我就把手上的東西丟進尼羅河
Or maybe I'll just toss what I have in the nile.
等等
Wait.
待在人世
Stay with the living.
- 她已經去到了我觸碰不了的地方  - 但你是神啊
She's gone beyond where I can reach her. But you're a god.
眾神們可以活上1000年
Gods may live 1,000 of your years,
但我們治癒不了死亡
but we cannot cure mortality.
該送她走上冥路了
It's time for her to walk the path.
你一定有辦法的
There must be something you can do.
我已經盡我所能了
I've done all I can.
永恆之神啊
Oh, thou who art everlasting,
派你的僕人前來引領死者前往新生吧
send your servant to guide the dead to new life.
阿努比斯 現身吧
Anubis, come forth.
你自由了
You are released.
地心之門已向你敞開
The doors of earth are open to you.
你得踏上旅途了
You must begin your journey.
她死時是一名奴隸
She died a slave.
沒有財寶的話 她絕對
Without treasure, she won't be allowed
通不過來世之門的
through the final gate.
你有什麼籌碼 ?
What do you offer?
她進不去來世的
She can't pass into the afterlife.
阿努比斯大人
For you, lord Anubis,
主建築師住在高高的大山上
governor of the bows, who is upon his mountain,
而我卻只有微笑能給你
I have only my smile.
如你所願
So be it.
薩亞 !
Zaya!
死人是不會對活人說話的
The dead don't speak to the living.
待在主路上
Stay on the path.
現在給我吧
Now give them to me.
- 你根本就沒幫上忙 !  - 我的眼睛
You've done nothing! My eyes.
你今後就一直盲目亂竄吧
Spend the rest of your days wandering around sightless.
我已經什麼都沒了 你明白嗎 ?
I have nothing to lose. Do you understand?
把眼睛給我
Give me my eyes.
我為了見她 願意做任何事 我寧願拚死一搏
I will do anything to see her again or I'll die trying.
你想躲過我的話 就少說點話
You want to hide from me? Learn to talk less.
給
Here.
另一隻呢 ?
Where's the other?
另一隻在哪 ?
我也不確定 不過我...
Well, I'm not exactly sure, but I...
我扭斷你的脖子
I'll snap your neck.
你一定很恨賽特殺了你父親
You must hate set for what he did to your father.
金字塔
The pyramid.
我知道怎麼進入金字塔
I know how to get into set's pyramid.
說說看
How?
快說
噢...
Oh...
那是他的力量之源 對吧 ?
It's where he keeps his power locked up, right?
如果我幫你潛入進去 你能殺了他麼 ?
If I could get you inside, could you kill him?
怎麼進去 ?
How would you do that?
我看了建築圖
I saw the plans.
給我說說
Tell me.
- 我直接帶你去  - 繼續
I'll show you. Go on.
如果你把薩亞帶回來
If you bring zaya back.
或許是有個方法
There may be a way.
進入了來世的人就無法回頭
No one may leave the afterlife once entered.
但是要穿過九大門
But the journey through the nine gates
需要好多天才行
will take several days to complete.
而只有國王才能讓阿努比斯回頭
And only the king can make Anubis turn back.
如果我趕在你的愛人到達來世之門面前
If I kill set and take back the crown
殺死賽特 並且奪回王冠的話
before your beloved reaches the final gate,
我或許能救她回來
I might be able to save her.
努力跟上
Try to keep up.
我的勇猛獵犬們
My magnificent bloody hounds.
你們是真正的埃及之子
You are the true sons of Egypt.
你們是我的鐵與血子
You are my children of iron and blood.
我真是為你們驕傲
No father could be more proud.
叛亂的眾神們已經被我們討伐
The rebel gods have choked on our Spears.
剩下的都逃進了奈芙蒂斯的要塞
The rest have retreated to nephthys' stronghold
他們在那做好了準備抵抗我們
where they now stand ready to face us.
但你們 我的沙漠軍團
But you, my legions of the desert,
將讓他們一敗塗地 !
will bring them reckoning!
拿上你們的金子吧 !
So take your fill of gold!
如果你們戰死沙場
And if you should fall in battle
踏上了九門旅途
and travel the nine gates,
告訴我哥哥你們崇拜的是誰 !
tell my brother who it is you worship!
賽特軍隊 稍息 立正 !
Division set! Amarn! Ta! Rai!
排好隊 !
Fall in!
先前進軍 !
Forward march!
大人
My lord.
你的皇家寶庫被人入侵了
Your royal treasury has been breached.
烏許...
Urshu...
那隻眼的作用
Wasn't the eye meant to
難道不是用來引誘荷魯斯的忠臣們自投羅網的嗎 ?
lure those loyal to horus to their deaths?
是的 大人
Yes, lord.
而你的陷阱...
And weren't your traps...
你當時是怎麼說的 ?
What was the term you used?
防盜 ?
Thief-proof?
是的 大人
Yes, lord.
你能追蹤到麼 ?
Can you pick up the trail?
我會找到他的
I'll find him.
把幫他的那個小偷
And find whichever of his allies
也給我找出來
was clever enough to steal back his eye.
他是個凡人 大人
It was a mortal, lord.
凡人 ?
A mortal?
她是誰 ?
Who is she?
他的僕人
His servant.
我為自己說一句 大人...
In my defense, lord...
相信我 我很好奇你的借口是什麼
Believe me, I'm very curious to hear what your excuse is.
但是現在不是時候
But not right now.
遵命 大人
Yes, lord.
看來你不是
Well, it appears you're not
埃及最聰明的凡人
the cleverest mortal in Egypt after all.
這個小偷才是
This thief is.
你的計劃是什麼 ?
So what is your plan?
想要殺死沙漠之神
To kill the god of the desert,
我們必須先殺死沙漠
we must kill the desert itself.
殺死沙漠 ?
Kill the desert?
沙漠怎麼殺 ?
How do you kill the desert?
我們得去我爺爺那
We must go to my grandfather's.
他會幫我們的
He'll help us with our task.
你爺爺 ?
Your grandfather?
你指的是拉 ? 太陽神拉 ?
You mean ra? The sun god ra?
那你爺爺在哪 ?
So where exactly is your grandfather?
你開玩笑的 對吧 ?
You're being funny, right?
你以為我有心情開玩笑 ?
You think I'd put any effort into trying to amuse you?
看來飛行能力在現在很有用
It seems flying would be useful right now.
我沒有兩隻眼就變不了身
Without both my eyes, I cannot transform.
我得為了力量祈禱才行
I need to pray for strength.
你這話一點都不鼓舞人心
Oh, that's not encouraging.
安靜點 否則我丟你下山去
Be silent or you'll reach the bottom of this mountain
下山速度可比上山快多了
much quicker than you reached the top.
偉大的拉神 傾聽我的呼喚
Great ra, know my name.
天空神請求你的懷抱
The lord of the air seeks your embrace.
爺爺 我需要你幫忙 拜託了 !
Grandfather, I need your help. Please!
真厲害 !
Impressed!
待在我的影子
Stay in my shadow.
- 為啥 ?  - 照我說的做就是
Why? Just do as I say.
偉大的拉主神萬歲
Hail, thou great god ra.
通常來說 當一隻鳥上了我的船
Normally, when a bird lands on my boat,
我會趕在它拉屎前就殺了它
I kill it before it can shit.
你這是什麼意思 ?
What is this?
你居然敢帶一個凡人來到萬物之源
You dare bring a mortal to the source of creation?
他對我很重要 我不能丟下他
He's valuable to me. I could not leave him behind.
啊 那你來做什麼 ?
Ah. Why have you come?
我想請您幫忙
I would only ask something of you.
既然是這樣的話
Oh, in that case,
那我還是停下手中的事 好好聽聽你的請求吧
I shall stop what I'm doing and heed your bidding.
爺爺 抱歉 我沒想要冒犯您
Grandfather, I'm sorry. I mean no disrespect.
你已經冒犯了
You don't know the difference.
待在這 保持安靜
Stay there. Be quiet.
我有活要做了
I have work to do.
如果你想要這凡人活命 就讓他去下甲板
And put the mortal below deck if you want him to live.
爬回你的陰影堨h 你這臭蟲 !
Crawl back to shadow, you stinking worm!
休想吃我創造的東西 !
You shall never feast on my creation!
盡量放馬過來吧
Try as you might.
如果我和你們住在
Things would be different if I could dwell
尼羅河花園 這個世界就完蛋了
amongst my children in the garden of the nile.
對抗惡魔阿波菲斯(冥府之蛇)是我的責任
It is my burden to fight the demon apophis
它每晚都要來
night after night.
埃及決不能被混亂毀滅
Egypt must never be destroyed by chaos.
看到了吧
So, you see,
有東西比賽特更可怕
there are things worse than set.
您錯了
You're wrong.
那只惡魔可沒有殺害我父親
That demon isn't the one who murdered my father.
也就是您兒子
Murdered your son.
他倆都是我兒子
They are both my sons.
他們在我眼堻ㄛO平等的
They were both equal in my eyes.
和我所有的創造物都一樣
As is all of my creation.
而命運的不確定性是我的意志
And the uncertainty of its destiny is my will.
你到底是來做什麼的 ?
So what is it actually that brings you here?
請讓我用神水灌滿水壺
Allow me to fill my flask with these waters.
神水又不是我的
The waters are not mine.
你想澆滅沙漠之火
You plan to quench the desert fire.
殺死賽特 成為國王
To kill set. To become king
遵從你父親的意願
as your father wished.
賜予我再次飛翔的力量
Grant me the power to fly again.
剛剛我就聽見你的祈禱了
I heard your prayer the first time.
我讓你來到了這
I let you come here
還允許你回去
and I Grant you passage home.
但在此之後呢 ?
But after that?
沒了雙眼
Without both my eyes,
我怕我的力量不夠擊敗賽特
I doubt I'm strong enough to beat set.
那就去磨煉
So become stronger.
難道你懶惰太久了
Have you been so lazy for so long
都忘了每一位神的生命都是一段旅程 ?
that you've forgotten every god's life is a journey?
當你誤入歧途時 你就會變弱
When you stray from your path, you grow weak.
喂 !
Hey!
你為什麼要讓這凡人待在你身邊 ?
Why are you lugging around this mortal?
他有膽量和我討價還價
He had the gall to strike a bargain with me.
啊
Ah.
反正帶著他也不會減你威風 是吧 ?
Not worth the papyrus it's written on, hmm?
重要嗎 ? 他只是一介凡人
What does it matter? He is but a mortal.
我不贊成賽特的統治
I do not approve of how set rules.
但我也不確定你比他好
But I'm uncertain you would be much better.
大人 最後一群叛亂眾神
Lord, the last of the rebel gods
也逃進了她的要塞
have retreated behind her walls.
所有人都進去了 ?
Every last one?
是的 大人
Yes, sir.
很好 他們成了甕中之鱉
Good. Then they're ripe for the picking.
這樣會不會太過了 ?
Isn't this a bit excessive?
反正她也希望他們奮戰致死
She'd want them to fight to the death anyway.
她可是你前妻
She was your wife.
那更有理由殺死她了
All the more reason to kill her.
從現在開始
From now on,
世界就得這麼走
this will be the way of things.
走我們的路
Our way.
你最好趕緊習慣下
Better get used to it.
作為女神怎麼能幹這種粗活 ?
Is it right that a goddess should perform such labor?
從你當上國王開始
Since you became king,
壽衣的需求量大增
the need for burial shrouds has been great.
你本能成為王后
You could have been a queen.
你很清楚我為什麼不能
You should know why I could not.
那我當初向你求婚的時候
Then, when I asked you to marry me,
你為什麼答應了我 ?
why did you say yes?
我還記得當時你在沙漠媢騁
I remember when you rode out of the desert.
勇猛 雄偉 帥氣
Impetuous. Dashing. So handsome.
我忍受著狂風 就為了待在你身邊
I braved those stinging winds just to be at your side.
想像著我們一起
And imagined the great deeds
能完成怎樣的偉業
we would accomplish together.
當時並不全是痛苦
It didn't all sting.
有一部分還是很甜蜜的
Some parts were sweet.
或許吧
Perhaps.
我現在還在想我們當初能幸福
I still thought we could have been happy.
你有了我就該知足了
I should have been enough to fulfill you.
沒有什麼東西能讓我滿足
Nothing can fulfill me.
所以拉神早預見到了
That's why ra was wise
所以才不讓你繁殖後代
to ensure you would never have a child.
為什麼 ?
Why?
這個秘密不能讓任何人知道
No one will know, until it's too late.
下一次 飛到地面上
Maybe next time, keep flying
再把翅膀收回去
until we're actually on the ground.
拉神賜予的東西 他一定會收回去
What ra gave, he took back.
他不是打算幫你嗎
I thought he was helping you.
我已經拿到目標了
I got what I needed.
尼羅河都無法澆滅賽特的火焰
The whole of the nile cannot quench set's fire.
但只需幾滴造物池堛滲咫
But a few drops from the water of creation can.
就能殺死沙漠
Kill the desert.
只要火焰沒了 賽特就會被削弱
With his fire gone, set will be weakened.
不堪一擊
Vulnerable.
如果我喝了那水會怎麼樣 ?
What would happen if I drank that?
你會精神煥發 然後死亡
You would be refreshed. Then you would die.
這可不對啊 造物之水居然能殺人
It doesn't seem right that the water of creation would kill.
是我會殺你 因為你浪費了我的水
I would kill you. For wasting my water.
這是什麼 ?
What's this?
免得你用雙手
So you don't have to bring me something to drink
捧著水給我喝
cupped in your hands.
我可不是你的奴隸
I'm not your slave.
我父親給我說過
My father taught me
神打凡人是髒了手
it's unworthy of a god to strike a man.
那他也該告訴你得挪挪身子
He should have taught you to get off your arse
自己找水喝
and get your own water.
抱歉 父親
Sorry, father.
簡直不能接受了
This is becoming unacceptable.
荷魯斯的眼睛在哪 ?
Where is the eye of horus?
就在你身後
Up your behind,
你關羊的地方
alongside the goats you keep up there.
荷魯斯的眼睛在哪 ?
Where is the eye of horus?
這
Right here.
我還以為你還盲目的
I thought you were crawling
在泥巴堨景u呢
sightless in the mud somewhere.
殺了他 !
Cut him down!
看見沒 兄弟們 ?
See, brothers?
沒有另一隻眼 他十分弱小
Without his other eye, he is weak.
就算我瞎了 聾了
Even if I were blind, deaf,
還缺胳膊少腿...
bereft of limbs...
你也不是我的對手
You're still no match for me.
你肯定很高興我沒摔死
You'll be glad to know I didn't fall to my death.
真感謝拉神啊
Praise ra.
如果我死了幫你殺賽特
The deal doesn't count if I die.
整個計劃的重點就是
The whole point is for zaya and I both
我和薩亞一起生活
to be here, together.
能呼吸 !
Breathing!
注意身後 !
Behind you!
荷魯斯 !
Horus!
親愛的拉神 請幫幫我們 !
Oh, ra, dear ra, please, help us!
荷魯斯 !
Horus!
我們要摔死了 !
We are going to die!
你先請
After you.
你確定你做得到嗎 ?
Are you sure you can do this?
我不都救了你麼 ?
I saved you, didn't I?
- 噢 是你救了我 ?  - 僅僅因為你對我還有用處
Oh, you saved me? Only because you're useful to me.
你知道還有其他什麼有用處嗎 ?
You know what would be useful?
你另一隻眼
Your other eye.
我可以幫你偷回來
I could steal it back for you, if you like.
別考驗我的耐心 凡人
Don't test my Patience, mortal.
我的名字不叫"凡人"
My name is not "Mortal."
那叫什麼 ?
What is it, then?
貝克
Bek.
好吧 貝克
Very well, bek.
從現在開始 道路會被監視著
The roads will be watched now.
賽特會派出最好的獵手
Set will send better hunters.
看來事情沒按照計劃進行 對吧 ?
Well, that didn't go according to plan, did it?
是的 大人
No, lord.
我侄子僅靠一隻眼就殺了這麼多人 ?
My nephew did all this with one eye?
我低估了他的力量
I underestimated his strength.
那孩子真夠難殺的
Tough to kill, that boy.
和他叔父一樣
Like his uncle.
他去哪了 ? 和誰一起的 ?
Where's he going? Who's he allying with?
他唯一的盟友就是那個凡人
His only ally is the mortal.
兩個人可算不上軍隊 對吧 ?
It's hardly an army, is it?
我偷聽了他們的談話
I overheard them.
那凡人和荷魯斯
The mortal spoke of a bargain
談好了一場交易
he'd made with horus.
這凡人膽子真夠大的
This is one ambitious mortal.
荷魯斯已經同意
Horus has agreed
將那凡人的女人救回人世
to bring the mortal's woman back from death.
你確定 ?
Are you sure?
我十分確定 大人
I'm certain of it, lord.
你真該去療療傷
You should really get that attended to.
- 謝謝大人  - 幹得好
Yes, lord. Thank you. Good job.
你從一開始就該交給我們來處理的
You should have trusted us with this from the start.
我們不是總能滿足你嗎 ?
Haven't we always left you satisfied?
那就再滿足我一次
Then satisfy me again.
你放過你妻子了嗎 ?
Did you let your wife live?
你和我遲早都會
Sooner or later, you and I will end up
變成那樣
just the same.
亡者之地以及九門
The land of the dead and its nine gates.
這儀器精準嗎 西方女主人 ?
Is it accurate, mistress of the west?
別這麼叫我
Don't call me that.
我已經拋棄過去了
I left all that behind.
很快 我將統治全世界
Soon, I will rule all the world.
而亡者之地就是
The land of the dead is the final kingdom
最後的王國
left standing.
你追求著擁有不了的東西
You want things you can't have.
我要你帶我過去
I want you to take me there.
但你是活人
But you're a living soul.
沒錯 但你當初為亡者做顧問的時候
Yes. And you were a living soul, too,
你也只是個活人
when you were counselor to the dead.
你很明白如果我回去 會有怎樣的下場
You know what's waiting for me if I go back.
你手上的手鐲
You have your little bracelet
能保護你不受惡魔加害
to protect you from those demons.
不是的
It's not that.
你很想念 對吧 ?
You miss it. Don't you?
把你塑造成現在這樣的黑暗
The darkness. What it brought out in you.
不是
No.
啊 你真不擅長撒謊 愛神
Ah, you're not so good, goddess of love.
我知道
I know.
那就帶我去
Then do this.
證明你對我的忠誠 然後我們就能擁有一切
Prove your loyalty to me. Then we can have everything.
兩人一起
Together.
荷魯斯...
Horus...
我的愛人
My love.
荷魯斯...
Horus...
你沒在你父親的墓穴 ?
You're not in your father's tomb?
我還在好奇他在哪呢
I was wondering where he was.
現在終於知道了
Now I know.
謝謝
Thanks.
作為一個能僅僅靠笑容就
For someone who bends the will of men
征服男人的女人
by batting her lashes,
你真不算聰明
you're not very clever.
他拿回眼睛多久了 ?
How long has he had his sight?
你幹嘛在乎 ?
Why do you care?
我現在是你的人了
I'm yours now.
我會遵從你的命令
I'll do as you've asked.
即使我殺了荷魯斯 ?
Even if I kill horus?
當然
Of course.
誰在乎他啊 ?
Who cares about him?
我以為你撒謊這麼久了
I'd have thought you'd be exhausted
早就累了呢
from so much lying.
我愛過奈芙蒂斯 而我砍下了她的翅膀
I loved nephthys once and I took her wings.
想想看我會怎麼對你
Imagine what I'll do to you.
你敢下手我就追殺你
Do that and I'll hunt you down.
讓我摸摸看
Let me touch.
估計這樣比逃往要好
I suppose it's better than running.
我們下次能選個好點的營地麼 ?
Can we find a less unpleasant campsite next time?
嗯
Hmm.
這堨H前是一個你想都沒想過花園
This used to be a garden like you've never seen.
發生了什麼事 ?
What happened?
這堿O我父親的第一座神廟
It was my father's first temple.
他大發慈悲 他對外開放了大門
In his generosity, he opened the grounds
好讓窮人們也能將自己親人埋葬在此
so the poor could bury their own here.
賽特破壞了他的遺產
Set has corrupted his teachings.
我父親很愛這個地方
My father loved this place.
所以賽特將他帶來此處屠殺了
So set brought him here to be butchered.
他的遺體被切成了14塊
His body was cut into 14 pieces.
心臟下落不明
The heart was never found.
賽特破壞了土地 ?
Set salted the earth?
不 那是我母親流淚造成的
No. It was my mother's tears.
她之後自刎了
Before she took her own life.
我辜負了他們
I failed them.
我很遺憾
I'm sorry.
拉神給我說過 我是在進行旅程
Ra told me I was on a journey.
如果我成功到達旅途盡頭 我就能重拾神力
And if I reach the end, I will be mighty again.
盡頭是什麼 ?
How does it end?
復仇
With vengeance.
用我的長矛穿入賽特的頭骨
Ends with my spear through set's skull.
那是風暴嗎 ?
Is that a storm?
可沒有烏雲啊
There's no clouds.
賽特的獵人們騎著寵物來了
Set's hunters riding their pets.
那玩意可不算寵物 貓才是寵物
Those aren't pets. A cat is a pet.
就我現在的實力 我抵抗不了它們的毒液
I can't withstand their venom. Not as I am now.
那我們快跑啊
Then I guess we should run.
- 逃跑 ?  - 凡人經常這樣做 !
Run? Mortals do it all the time!
跑快點 !
Run faster!
快不了了 !
I can't!
跑快點 !
Run faster!
快不了了 !
I can't!
快跑 !
Come on!
- 我們得殺了它們  - "我們" ?
We have to kill them. "We"?
釣魚的首則是什麼 ?
When you go fishing, what's most important?
- 我不釣魚  - 就是魚餌的質量
I don't fish. It's the quality of the bait.
太危險了
It's too dangerous.
你在為我擔心 ?
Are you worried about me?
不是 只是我現在投矛的精準度大不如前了
No, it's just my aim with a spear is not what it was.
那投之前靠近點
Then get closer before you throw it.
喂 美女 !
Hey! Beautiful!
我指的是蛇 !
I meant the snake!
起作用了 我們再來一次
That worked great. Let's go again.
這次 誘餌得多引誘點時間
This time, the bait needs to dangle longer.
我得攻擊它身後的弱點
I must strike the weak spot from behind.
你是怎麼知道它們有弱點的 ?
And how do you know they have a weak spot?
我不知道 但是肯定有 對吧 ?
I don't. But they must, right?
快去 !
Go!
很好 你把它惹怒了
Excellent! You've made it angry.
真不幸你現在飛不了了
Too bad you can no longer fly.
你也不能
Neither can you.
是你 !
You!
閉嘴讓路就是
Just shut up and stay out of my way.
漂亮妹子 你可不是打仗的料
Pretty girl, you don't belong in battle.
燒死她 !
Burn her!
真是可愛的生物啊
What a lovely creature you are.
我來幫你
Let me help you.
燒死她 !
Burn her!
你感覺很冷
You are so very cold.
為自己加熱吧 我命令你
Warm yourself. I command you.
快走
Quickly.
此墓地歡迎你
Your company was preferable.
真是瘋了 !
Outrageous!
救了你一命不用客氣
You're welcome for saving your life.
我雙目失明坐在父親墓穴堛漁伬
So while I was sitting blind in my father's tomb,
你卻和挖出我雙眼的神
you shared a bed with the god
共度春宵
who pulled out my eyes.
為什麼我要把自己的美貌浪費在盲人身上 ?
Why would I waste this on someone who can't see?
那我為什麼要再次信任你 ?
Why would I ever trust you again?
他殺死了所有不臣服於他的神
He's slaying all the gods who won't bow to him.
其中也包括我
That includes me.
我們準備入侵賽特的神廟
We're breaking into set's temple.
由荷魯斯殺了他
Horus is going to kill him.
那你們計劃怎麼進去 ?
How were you planning to get in?
他 ?
Him?
他看過建築圖 他識路
He's seen the plans. He knows the way.
那斯芬克斯怎麼辦 ? 難道你忘了 ?
What about the sphinx? Have you forgotten about that?
"斯芬克斯" ?(人面師身的怪物)
"Sphinx"?
賽特抓它來守護火種
Set captured it to guard his fire.
如果進去的人回答不出謎題
It will kill mercilessly all who enter
它就會毫不留情的殺死你
if they cannot answer its riddle.
你回答得出謎題 對吧 ?
You can answer the riddle, right?
那我們去請求托特幫忙
We shall ask thoth for help.
神經病才會去聽托特說教
Why would you ever do that on purpose?
找他幫忙才不會被殺
So we won't have to die any sooner than is absolutely necessary.
走吧
Let's go.
這裙子是他送你的 ?
Did he give you that dress?
我從幾條裙子媬麊
I chose from what was provided.
所以你從中選了一條
So you chose the one you thought
最能取悅他的裙子
would please him the most.
- 我穿裙子是為了取悅自己  - 嗯
- I dress to please myself. - Hmm.
怎麼 不喜歡嗎 ?
Why? You don't like it?
太過了
It's too much.
我就是太過了女神
I'm the goddess of too much.
我都給過你好多次
And there's plenty I've given you
你當時卻不嫌多
you've never found excessive.
啊
Ah.
現在又太少了
Now it's maybe too little.
你以前可沒這樣難取悅啊
You never used to be so hard to please.
你在拖慢我們的速度
You're slowing us down.
噢
Ooh.
我覺得你這眼罩把你襯托得很流氓
I think it makes you look roguish.
那我以前是怎樣的 ?
What did I look like before?
- 健忘  - 噢 !
Oblivious. Oh!
但還是挺可愛的
But in a cute way.
什麼健忘 ?
Oblivious of what?
就是這樣 你總覺得我應該討好你
Exactly. You always did take me for granted.
啥 ?
What?
你找回眼睛後 就該來救我的
With your eye back, you should have come to get me.
- 噢 ?  - 難道我還沒滿足你嗎 ?
Oh? Don't I mean enough to you?
乖乖幫我找點淨水喝吧
Be a dear and fetch me some clean water.
說個"請"不行嗎 ?
Would it kill you to say "Please"?
我現在真沒心情吵架
I'm really not in the mood to argue.
去給我找水喝 我命令你
Go get it for me. I command you.
你們這群神都是一個尿性 對吧 ?
You're all the same, aren't you?
她叫什麼名字 ?
What's her name?
我能讓任何男人 女人 神 野獸都聽從我的命令
I can make any man, woman, god or beast do my bidding.
除非他們心屬他人
Unless their heart belongs to another.
你戀愛了
You're in love.
她叫薩亞
Her name's zaya.
真對不起
I'm so sorry.
我答應過她一個舒適的家庭
I promised her a proper home.
有足夠的錢養家 體面的生活
Money for a family. Respectability.
我卻什麼也沒做到
I gave her nothing.
噢 她如果不愛你
Oh, she wouldn't have been with you
就不會和你在一起了
if she didn't love you.
相信我 我很清楚
Believe me, I know.
我會彌補她的
I'm going to make it up to her.
但她不是...
But I thought she...
荷魯斯會救她回來
Horus is going to bring her back.
他這麼說的 ?
He said that?
我知道想要看穿
I know it's hard to see past his
他外表那暴脾氣和復仇的慾望很難 但是...
short temper and proclamations of revenge but...
他不是壞人
He's not so bad.
確實很難看穿
It is hard to see.
到了
There it is.
那是他嗎 ?
Is that him?
- 他們 ?  - 當然不是
Them? Of course not.
那他們是誰 ?
Then who are they?
他信任的僕人們
His trusted servants.
他只相信他自己
He only trusts himself.
生長得很肥大
Rich with generous compost.
顏色鮮艷
Colorful.
主要是綠色和紅色光譜
Mainly in the green and red spectrums.
中間由
Variegated varieties with
無數種小花瓣組成
inflorescences composed of multiple florets,
每一瓣都被改進過
each with a modified calyx.
聖言睿智神 我們需求你的智慧
Wise lord of the sacred word, we seek your counsel.
一個種子被連根拔起
Once, a weed, uprooted and burned.
現在卻想重回豐饒的土地
Now prized for the vigor of its oils
以及長出自己的枝葉
and the sustenance of its leaves.
但真相是什麼 ?
But what is its truth?
你 ! 轉過身去
You! Turn around.
你喜歡看後面 ?
You prefer the view from behind?
不是 好吧 是
No, I... well, yes.
你很清楚我撒不了慌 轉過去
You know I can't lie. Turn.
我可不打算冒險
I'm not going to risk
看著你那勾人的眼神
looking at those tricky eyes of yours.
- 47  - 什麼 ?
Forty-seven. Excuse me?
我目前已記錄知識的百分比
The percentage of knowledge I have so far recorded.
還沒到一半呢
I'm not even half done.
- 托特 我只需要...  - 斯芬克斯謎語的答案
Thoth, I only need... The answer to the riddle of the sphinx.
小孩都能猜到你來的目的
A child could deduce why you're here.
去問出謎題
Go ask the riddle
然後回來講給我聽
and come back and relay it to me.
我就給你解掉
I'll solve it.
那我們其中一人就得死
One of us would have to die.
那就抽籤吧
Well, draw lots.
- 和我們一起去  - 哈 !
Come with us. Ha!
- 我和你睡一晚  - 嗯
One night. I'll give you one night. Hmm...
才不行
No, you won't.
必須趕在賽特毀滅我們所有人之前阻止他
Set must be stopped before he destroys us all.
你明白這道理 對吧 ?
You see the wisdom in that, don't you?
我不能拿我的大腦冒險
This is far too important to risk.
我可以背誦出群星的真名
I can recite the true names of the stars.
我知道
I know.
我見過由沙和水組成的世界
I've seen the world created from sand and water.
嗯哼
Mmm-hmm.
我大腦埵野宇宙的知識
I contain all the wisdom in the universe.
比什麼王冠寶貴多了
More precious than some crown.
哈 ! 我想到了 !
Ha! I have it!
這是秘密 這是精華 這是真理
Its mystery. Its essence. Its truth.
這只是生菜而已 !
It's lettuce!
你父親自己大意了
Your father dropped his guard.
那不僅僅是愚蠢之極的行為
That was not only extremely stupid,
搞的我現在必須記錄下我所知的一切
but now I'm forced to write down everything I know
為了預防賽特找我開戰
as a defense against the remote possibility
的可能性
that set's war finds me.
我真抱歉我父母的遺體
I'm sorry that the corpses of my parents
給你造成了不便
have inconvenienced you.
接受你的道歉了 現在滾吧 !
Apology accepted. Now, get out!
你必須得幫我們 !
But you have to help us!
小心點
Careful.
我人數比你多
I outnumber you.
等等 !
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
沒關係 由我來吧
It's fine. I'll do it.
我剛還以為你是只離群狒狒
I thought you were a stray baboon.
我說了 由我去面對斯芬克斯
I told you I'd be the one to face the sphinx.
你失敗的幾率就快突破雲霄了
Your chance of failure is overwhelming.
沒錯 可在它殺死我之前
I'm sure. But before it kills me
我會告訴它
I'm going to tell it that I asked
我叫過睿智神一起來
the god of wisdom to come
但他卻害怕猜不中謎題
but he was afraid he'd get the answer wrong.
這就是你最好的戰術了 ?
This is the cleverest strategy you could devise?
激將法 ?
Playing on my ego?
你覺得我有多自負 ?
How vain do you think I am?
額...
Um... hmm.
好吧...
Yes, well...
好吧
Fine.
好吧 !
Fine!
我們走吧
Let's go.
拜
Bye.
幹得漂亮
Well done.
謝謝誇獎
Thank you.
你明知薩亞永遠回不來了
You know his zaya can never come back.
國王根本沒有這種力量
The king doesn't have the power.
阿努比斯也沒這種力量
Anubis doesn't have the power.
你騙了他
You deceived him.
他很可能會在進入賽特的金字塔途中就死掉
He will probably die trying to break into set's pyramid.
他的交易籌碼就是生命
He offered his life.
那是因為他以為自己能救回愛人
Because he thought he could save her.
他自己願意相信 我能怎樣
He believes what he wants to believe.
你瞎的地方不止是眼睛
You've been blind in more ways than one.
你真見證了世界的誕生 ?
You really watched the world come into being?
我從不撒謊
I don't lie.
那你是從哪看的
Where were you watching it from,
不是所有事物都還沒誕生嗎 ?
if nothing had been created yet?
如果我解釋出口
If I even attempted to explain,
你的小腦袋肯定受不了 直接七竅流血
your brain would liquefy and run out of your ears.
復仇之路又不是我選的
I did not choose a path of revenge.
我根本沒選擇這一切
I chose none of this.
你倒是給我說 我到底有什麼力量 ?
You tell me what kind of power do I really have?
你有彌補這件事的力量
You have the power to make this right.
他有權利知道真相
He deserves to know the truth.
我需要他帶我們進去 澆滅賽特的火焰
I need him to get us in to choke set's fire.
如果他拒絕了 我們都會死 難道你希望這樣 ?
If he refuses, we'll all die. Is that what you want?
橫穿進去太危險了
It's too dangerous to cross the plain.
我們等到晚上再行動
We'll wait for darkness.
可我們要沒時間了
But we're running out of time.
- 我說我們現在就穿過去  - 我說了等到晚上
I say we cross now. And I say we wait.
在你們分開的這段時間 她從沒忘記過你
All the time you were apart, she never forgot you.
哈索爾心堣@直愛著你
You've always been in hathor's heart, you know.
沒錯 但她的心可夠大的
Yes, but she's got a big heart.
都夠住進好多人了
Room enough for a crowd in there.
告訴我 睿智的天空神
Tell me, oh, wise lord of the air.
你覺得賽特是為什麼放了你一條生路 ?
Why do you think set let you live?
她為了愛才屈身於他的
She did it for love.
而你卻要以此懲罰她 ?
You'd punish her for that?
我根本不需要她幫忙
I didn't want her help.
我只期望過一件事
I only ever wanted one thing.
知道嗎 我覺得所有人都是傻子
You know, I think everyone's a fool.
但你比大部分人都傻  大人
But you, my lord, are bigger than most.
你在想她嗎 ?
Are you thinking about her?
你當然在想了
Of course you are.
我以前被稱作西方女主人
I was once known as the mistress of the west.
我的責任是幫助亡魂
My duty was to help dead souls
找到前往來世的路
make their way to the afterlife.
你去過亡者之地 ?
You traveled to the land of the dead?
我可是愛神 當然也愛著亡者
I'm the goddess of love. Even to those who have died.
我以前很年輕 很容易被誘惑
I was young. Easily seduced.
"誘惑" ?
"Seduced"?
惡魔
Demons.
這手鐲封印著它們
This keeps them at bay.
42星手鐲
The bracelet of 42 stars.
每一顆星都代表荷魯斯為釋放我殺死的惡魔
One for each of the demons horus slayed to free me.
當時我就愛上他了
That's when I knew I loved him.
也得讓薩亞知道你在為她奮鬥才行
Zaya needs to know you're fighting for her.
這樣她才不會失去希望
So she does not lose hope.
薩亞
Zaya.
薩亞 ? 薩亞 ? 能聽見我嗎 ?
Zaya? Zaya? Can you hear me?
薩亞 ?
Zaya?
你是誰 ?
Who is it?
誰在說話 ?
Who's there?
- 哈索爾 西方女主人  - 女主人
- Hathor, mistress of the west. - Mistress.
我在活人世界與你對話
I speak to you from the land of the living.
你的愛人在我身邊
Your beloved is with me.
- 貝克 ?  - 薩亞 是我
Bek? Zaya, it's me.
我就知道你能想出辦法的
I knew if there was a way, you would find it.
但是我看不到你
But I can't see you.
聽著 我們能再次重逢
Listen, we can be together again.
你可以重回人世
You can return.
怎麼回 ?
But how?
我幫助荷魯斯
I'm helping horus.
而作為回報 他也會幫助我們
In return, he's going to help us.
你真是我愛的那個貝克嗎 ?
It is really the bek I love?
沒錯 薩亞 我自己也不敢相信
I know, zaya. I can hardly believe it myself.
我居然在相信眾神
Bek, me, trusting the gods.
我之前說錯了 薩亞
But I was wrong, zaya.
荷魯斯是位明神 如你所言
Horus is a just god, as you said he would be.
你現在肯定在想 "我早就說過了"
You're probably thinking, "I told you so," Right now.
沒錯 確實想了下
Well, yes. Just a little bit.
能聽見你的聲音真是太好了
It's so good to hear your voice.
一切都會好起來的 薩亞 相信我
Everything's going to be fine, zaya, trust me.
荷魯斯會救你回來
Horus is going to bring you back.
我相信他
I know he will.
貝克 ?
Bek?
貝克 你還在嗎 ?
Bek, are you there?
亡者是不允許和活人對話的
It is forbidden for the dead to speak with the living.
快去
Go.
堶惘陪蚋鉠
There's a wheel inside.
轉動的話 沙子就會停下來
When you turn it, the sand stops moving.
我們只需要通過大門就行
We just need to go through the door.
好在你看過建築圖
Good thing you saw those plans.
如果不知道是哪個的話
If you didn't know which one it was,
想進去真是不可能
this would truly be impossible.
- 貝克 ?  - 嗯 ?
Bek? Yes?
你知道門在哪吧 ?
You do know which is the door, right?
當然 是...
Yes, of course, it's...
這個
This one.
不對 是那個
No, no, it's... It's that one.
不對 是這個 !
No, no, it's this one!
祝我好運吧
Roll the bones.
你是猜的 ?
You guessed?
額...
Well...
我真不喜歡你這靠運氣的做法
I find your dependence on chance troubling.
如果你能繼續活下去
If you continue to survive,
我可能得好好研究下你了
I may need to study you further.
好了 哪條路通往斯芬克斯 ?
Now, which way to the sphinx?
國王神殿的入侵者
Trespassers in the house of the king,
回答我的謎題 要麼領死
answer my riddle or cease to be.
說吧
Go on.
我等著呢
I'm waiting.
我不存在於過去
I never was.
但我永遠存在
Am always to be.
沒人見過我的面目
No one ever saw me, nor ever will.
而我是所有生靈活著的追求
And yet I am the confidence of all who live and breathe.
我是什麼 ?
What am I?
秩序 你是秩序
Order. You are order.
我從沒懷疑過你
I never doubted you.
不對
Incorrect.
請再試一次
Try again. Please.
這答案這麼準確
That was a completely suitable answer.
你是純粹
You are purity.
又錯了
Wrong again.
"不存在於過去"
"What never was."
"但永遠存在"
"Always to be."
也就是在未來的 不存在的 想像出來的
In the future. Non-existent. Imaginary.
但是
Yet...
確實存在過 而且"沒存在於過去"
Yet it exists and "Never was."
- "永遠存在"  - 托特...
"Always to be." Thoth...
而我是所有生靈活著的追求
Yet I'm the confidence of all who live and breathe.
凡人就得呼吸 !
Mortals live and breathe!
要不別用神的思維來思考
Maybe stop thinking like a god.
那我還不如直接不思考了呢
Then I might as well stop thinking.
托特 !
Thoth!
等下 我想到了 !
Wait, wait, I have it!
你是明日
You are tomorrow.
該死
Oh, bother.
只需一滴
One drop.
不 !
No!
我真該謝謝你
I should thank you.
你把他從圖書館堣牏F出來 省了我一趟
You lured him from his library so that I didn't have to.
最後的碎片
The final piece.
你個懦夫
You coward.
把陷阱打開和我戰鬥
Open this gate and fight me.
又打 ?
Again?
難道她還沒看夠你一敗塗地嗎 ?
Hasn't she's seen you lose enough?
你就不能容我
Can't you allow me to spare you
在你死前 放過你
one last moment of embarrassment
最後的尊嚴嗎 ?
before you die?
住手 !
Stop!
認出來了嗎 ?
Recognize this?
他有沒有給你說過他能救活你女人 ?
Did he tell you he could bring your woman back from death?
那是不可能的
It's not possible.
就算是我也不能
Not even for me.
你覺得我會信你 ?
You expect me to believe you?
我沒必要撒謊
I don't have to lie.
要不然一個雙目失明的廢神
How else would a blind, useless god
要怎麼做才能讓你幫他 ?
get you to help him?
去啊
Go on.
問他吧
Ask him.
- 快倒啊  - 是真的嗎 ?
Pour it in. Is it true?
貝克 快倒 !
Bek, pour it in!
不 !
No!
真遺憾你沒站我這邊
Shame you weren't on my side.
我很尊敬那些不怕死的人
I admire someone that doesn't let death stand in his way.
不過 這就是愛情的下場
But this is what love gets you.
你倆一起死在我神殿
It's quite fitting that you'll both
真是太適合不過了
die together here in my house.
我會想念這段對話的
I'll miss the conversation.
以及你們的死相
And the rest.
你阻止了我復仇
You denied me vengeance.
薩亞相信你是
Zaya thought you were
所有創造物堻怜隊j的
the greatest thing in all of creation.
每天每日 她都祈禱著你能拯救埃及
Every day, she prayed for you to save Egypt,
但你沒回來
but you didn't come.
我當時在墓穴 我聽不到祈禱
I was in a tomb. I didn't hear.
不對 你是根本沒聽
No, you didn't listen.
你只在乎你的復仇計劃
All you care about is your stupid vengeance.
我都開始覺得自己之前錯怪你了
I started to think I was wrong about you.
但我現在終於認清了事實
But I've finally learned the lesson of the gods.
你們根本不在乎我們
We don't matter to you.
你現在清楚了吧
Well, now you know.
阿努比斯 現身吧
Anubis, come forth.
女主人
Mistress.
你還是如同破曉般美麗
You are still as lovely as the first dawn.
哈索爾 你幹嘛 ?
Hathor, what are you doing?
這位凡人的愛人身上無任何財寶
This mortal's beloved bears no treasure for the scales.
我們幫幫她吧
Perhaps we can help her.
這要求太過了 女主人
You ask much, mistress.
必須獻上一個非常特殊的珍寶
It would require a very special treasure indeed.
不
No.
- 不 !  - 比如這個 ?
No. No! Like this?
如果是你的話 西方女主人
For you, mistress of the west?
可以
Yes.
賜予他前去將財寶給她的機會
Grant him passage to give it to her himself.
你能最後一次與她相見
You will see her one last time.
謝謝你
Thank you.
不行 不許你這樣
No, no, I forbid it.
我們都背上了欺騙貝克的罪名
We're both guilty of deceiving bek.
這樣才能贖罪
This will make amends.
不能用這種方法 不能你自己送死
Not like this. Not with you.
我命令你放開我
I command you to release me.
你又命令不了我 你明知原因
You can't command me. You know why.
我是愛神
I'm the goddess of love.
如果我不幫他們 那我算什麼
If I don't do this, I'm nothing.
我不能再失去你了
I can't lose you again.
拿去吧
Take it.
去做該做之事吧
Do what you need to do.
真相之廳
The hall of two truths.
我們會在這接受審判
Where we shall be judged.
上前來
Step forward.
你獻上什麼 ?
What do you offer?
往前走
Step forward.
我要永生了 !
I shall live forever!
你獻上什麼 ?
What do you offer?
往前走
Step forward.
上前來
你獻上什麼 ?
What do you offer?
薩亞
Zaya.
貝克
Bek.
賽特
Set,
奈芙蒂斯的羽翼
receive the golden wings of nephthys.
願羽翼保護他免受加害
May they protect him from those who would harm.
托特的大腦 睿智神
The karr of thoth, god of wisdom.
願他擁有遠古的智慧
Allow him knowledge of old.
奧西奡答漱萲
The heart of osiris.
賜予他所有土地的統治權
Grant him dominion over all lands.
全知之眼
The all-seeing eye.
獎勵他不受敵人欺騙
Reward him so no enemy can deceive.
您看上去真是太輝煌了 大人
You look glorious, lord.
我知道
I know.
父親...
Father...
我看到你的塔了 真宏偉
I noticed the tower. Impressive.
我為你建造的
I built it for you.
如果建的再高一點 都能擋道我的道了
If it were any taller, it would be in my way.
把眼睛從這艘船上移開吧
Turn your eyes from your sails
看看我取得的成就
and look at everything I've done.
連奧西奡絨ㄗS做到的事
What osiris never could.
我統治著眾神
I rule all that breathes.
以及低階的凡人
And all that is breathed upon.
任何人都不會比太陽強大
None is mightier below the sun.
那就給我以榮譽 就如我給您榮譽一樣
Then honor me as I've honored you.
如果你講榮譽的話
If honor had been your intent,
你當時就不會殺害你哥哥了
you might have abstained from murdering your brother.
所以你還是注意到凡間的事了
So you do see everything down there.
告訴我 父親 你在乎凡間的情況嗎 ?
Tell me, father, do you care what happens?
我比你想的更在乎
I care more than you know.
那為什麼我獨自被驅逐
Then why was I cast out alone
被迫踏上熱沙之路
to walk on burning sand
而我哥哥卻能光著腳
while my brother played barefoot
享受著尼羅河的清涼 ?
by the shores of the nile?
您為什麼讓奧西奡絲禨磥 ?
Why did you make osiris king?
為什麼你要給他一個兒子
And why did you give him a son?
而卻不讓我擁有製造生命的機會 ?
And yet you denied me the chance to even give life.
這是你的測驗
This was your test.
你可沒測驗他
You didn't test him.
我給了奧西奡筑J及王冠的權利
I gave osiris the crown of Egypt.
而當測驗之時來臨時 他沒有死抓住權利不放
And when the time came, he didn't cling to his power.
他贈與給了其他人 他通過了測試
He gave it away freely. He passed his test.
而我覺得我也通過了測試
And I'd wager I've passed mine.
還沒有
Not yet.
沒錯...
It's true...
我是不想讓你擁有後代
I did not want you to have children.
這是善意之舉
This was a kindness,
因為我不想讓你像我這樣
because I did not want you to miss them
倍受想念孩子的煎熬
as terribly as I have.
想念 ?
Miss them?
我需要你接替我
I need you to take my place.
這 ?
Here?
這奡N是你測驗的終點 兒子
This is how your test ends, my son.
再也沒有比這更重的負擔了
There is no greater burden.
但也意味著巨大的榮耀
But no greater honor.
你的所作所為都能被原諒
All you have done can be forgiven.
你想讓我與這頭怪物作戰
You expect me to joust with this beast
夜以繼夜 直到死去 ?
night after night until I die?
你想要什麼 ?
What do you want?
不朽之身
Immortality.
不朽就在來世等著我們所有人
Immortality awaits us all in the afterlife.
我不想死 我想活著
I don't want to die. I want to live.
永遠活著
Forever.
在我統治的凡間
Down there in the lands I conquered.
我的王國
My kingdom.
這才是我應得的獎賞
This should be my reward.
怎麼做 ? 能達成這個目標的方法是萬惡之最
How? The only way to achieve this is unthinkable.
必須吞噬掉...
One would need to devour...
來世本身
The afterlife itself.
你要讓世間充滿混沌 ?
You would unleash chaos upon creation?
你願意毀滅一切 ?
You would destroy everything?
不是毀滅 而是重塑
Not destroy. Reshape it.
我會接替你的位置
I will take your place.
但我可不會坐在你這破船上
But it won't be sitting on some damn boat.
沒有神能撐得住太陽能量
No god could withstand that.
我可不只是一個神
I'm not just one god.
你獻上什麼 ?
What do you offer?
這手鐲能買到通往來世的路
This will buy you a place in the afterlife.
不
No.
沒有你我不去
Not without you.
來世之門被破壞了 !
The gate has been broken!
混沌正在擴張
Chaos spreads.
阿波菲斯會毀滅亡者之地的
Apophis shall destroy this land.
荷魯斯是我們唯一的希望了
Horus is our only hope now.
他根本不是你想像中的神 薩亞
He's not the god you think he is, zaya.
他對我撒謊
He lied to me.
再給他個機會
Give him another chance.
他都是因為有你幫忙才能走到這一步
He only got this far because of you.
我的力量不是無限的
My strength is not infinite.
如果天空神有拯救世界的計劃
If the lord of the air has any plan to rectify this,
那他最好抓緊了
he should do so with haste.
如果你不相信他 那就相信我
If you don't trust him, trust me.
我知道我們會重逢的
I know we'll be together again.
拉神倒下了
Ra has fallen.
賽特釋放了混沌
Set has unleashed chaos.
那我們怎麼阻止他 ?
So how do we stop him?
你從不放棄 對吧 ?
You never give up, do you?
那是因為薩亞叫我別放棄
Only because zaya told me not to.
你沒告訴她我倆的約定 ?
You didn't tell her about our bargain?
我告訴她了
Yes, I did tell her.
但不知道為何 她還是相信你
But for some reason, she still believes in you.
我們必須回首都去
We must return to the capital.
那我們得走很長一段路了
Then we have a long walk ahead of us.
我覺得用飛的比較好
I prefer flying.
奈芙蒂斯
Nephthys.
就算已經死了 她也想幫助我們
Even beyond death, she's trying to help us.
來吧 惡魔 !
Come, demon!
賽特拿著拉神的長矛
Set has ra's spear.
他在引誘阿波菲斯到尼羅河去
He's drawing apophis to the nile,
生命的源頭
to the source of all life.
為什麼 ?
Why?
為了吸乾尼羅河 毀掉世間萬物
To drink it. To destroy all creation.
拉神還沒死 只有他能阻止這一切
Ra isn't dead. And only he can make this right.
但他需要自己的長矛
But he needs his spear.
那我們怎麼搶回來 ?
So how do we get it back?
看來是時候釣魚了
Maybe it's time we go fishing.
我效忠於您 我請求您的幫助
I come in your service, I ask for your help.
建築師
Builder.
我們有事找你
We have need of you.
這是最偉大的前無古人後無來者的建築
It is the single greatest architectural achievement
沒有之一
that ever was and ever will be.
我的...
My...
額 賽特大人的方尖碑
I mean, lord set's obelisk
準確高2200腕尺(約976米)
stands exactly 2,220 cubits tall.
不多不少
And not a rod off.
材料為70億塊花崗岩
Built from seven billion blocks of granite,
50億塊圖拉石灰岩平板
five billion slabs of tura limestone,
以及900萬塔蘭特金子(2億4300萬公斤)
and nine million talents of gold.
而又有多少奴隸的性命呢 ?
And the lives of how many slaves?
5930個
5,930.
不對 等下
No, wait.
應該是5931個
Make that 5,931.
別 你需要他幫你到達塔頂
Don't! You need him to get to the roof.
頂上見
I'll see you up top.
你站在他身邊 就好像他是你朋友一樣
You stood beside him as if he were your friend.
我知道這是什麼感覺
Oh, I know how it feels.
被神明寵幸
Favor of a god.
是很讓人陶醉
It's intoxicating.
真遺憾你追隨錯神了
I'm sorry you picked the wrong one to follow.
他還有進步空間
He's improving.
你女人已經死了 不是嗎 ?
Your woman's still dead, isn't she?
真遺憾 她真是個漂亮妹子
Shame. Such a pretty girl.
嗯...
Hmm...
皮膚也很柔軟
Such lovely soft skin.
足夠通往天堂的財富
Riches for the afterlife.
看到沒 ? 我已經準備好去死了
You see? I'm ready to die.
來吧 阿波菲斯 !
Come, apophis!
你真該待在沙底下的
You should have stayed under the sand.
我能理解為了王冠而殺人
I can understand killing for a crown,
但你這樣真是瘋了
but this is madness.
你當然不明白了
Of course you don't understand.
你怎麼明白得了 ?
How could you?
受寵兒子生的受寵兒子
Favored son of a favored son.
順帶一提
By the way,
阿波菲斯會吞噬掉亡者之地
apophis is going to eat the land of the dead.
你是去不了來世了
You'll never make it to the afterlife now.
啥 ?
What?
現在是誰追隨錯了神明啊 ?
Who picked the wrong god now?
我以後會挺想念這場叔侄重逢的
I think I may actually miss our little get-togethers.
但你仍然不是我的對手
But you're still no match for me.
你說得對
You're right.
我只是個誘餌而已
I'm just the bait.
而你現在變成了臭蟲
Now you're just becoming a pest.
荷魯斯 !
Horus!
難道你不覺得你的眼睛
You don't think your eye might have been
比一個受傷的小偷更重要嗎 ?
more useful than a wounded thief?
沒錯
Probably, yes.
我之前對不起你
I'm sorry for everything I've done to you.
包括現在
Including this.
接受了
Accepted.
我是說過我會偷來另一隻眼
I told you I'd steal your other eye.
但你應該好心告訴我說
But you could have saved me some trouble
你並不需要的
and told me you didn't need it.
拉神給我指了路
Ra showed me the way,
但我當時沒有聽進去
but I didn't listen.
我以為是要靠另一隻眼才能變身
I believed I needed my eye to transform,
但我的旅程並不是不擇手段尋求復仇
but my journey isn't to seek revenge at all costs.
而是保護我的人民
It is to protect my people.
別再自我祝賀了
Stop congratulating yourself.
你還有保護工作要做呢
You've got more protecting to do.
快看 新國王
Behold, the new king.
我以前認為你是眾神中最偉大的一個
I thought you were the greatest of all the gods.
瞧瞧你現在這樣子
Now look at you.
你什麼都沒了
You have nothing.
我的確是最偉大的神
I am the greatest god.
我饒過了你一次
I spared you once.
對吧 ?
Huh?
我放了你一條生路
I showed you mercy.
我可不會犯這種錯
I won't make that mistake.
爺爺 現在還有時間
Grandfather, there's still time.
夠了 怪物 !
Enough, beast!
謝謝你
Thank you.
我們配合真不錯
We make a good team.
你確定你不是神 ?
Are you sure you're not a god?
我是什麼神 ?
What would I be the god of?
愚蠢神 ?
Stupidity?
奇跡神
The impossible.
貝克 ?
Bek?
我從沒欠過任何人任何事
I have never been in debt.
而我卻欠了你的人情 孫子
And yet I am in debt to you, grandson.
有什麼要求都可以提
Ask whatever you will.
大山都會臣服於你面前
Mountains will kneel before you.
狂風也會遵從你的指示
The winds will do your bidding.
快點回答 阿波菲斯還沒放棄
Answer quickly, for apophis still hungers.
而夜晚總會降臨
And night is always coming.
我什麼也不要
I want nothing.
除了一件我給予不了的東西
Except what's impossible for me to give.
我這是...
Am I...
你回來了
You've returned.
貝克
Bek?
幫幫她起身吧
You might want to help her.
薩亞
Zaya.
貝克
Bek.
薩亞 ?
Zaya?
我叫荷魯斯
I'm horus.
大人
My lord.
你不是說這是不可能做到的嗎
I thought this was impossible.
不可能 ? 沒錯
Impossible? Yes.
拉主神 光之王萬歲 !
Hail ra, lord of light!
故事最後智慧被找到了
And so wisdom had been found.
測驗也被通過了 第二次機會也被賜予了
Tests had been passed. Second chances given.
重新生活
To live again.
王國再次團結
To be whole again.
荷魯斯悼念了他的父母
Horus mourned his parents.
他們在來世安息
They had long since passed into the afterlife.
他很清楚是拉神的智慧
But he knew it was the wisdom of ra
才保證了來世之門的敞開
that the final gate would remain as it had always been.
一個牢不可破的在人世和永生之間的屏障
An unbreakable barrier between this life and immortality.
你覺得我準備好沒 ?
You think I'm ready?
嗯 真正的就緒
Hmm, true readiness
總所周知是很難做到的
is a notoriously difficult state to achieve.
不過你也夠接近了
But you're close enough. Hmm.
起身吧 荷魯斯...
Arise, horus...
全埃及之王
King of all Egypt.
從現在開始
From this moment on,
想進入來世必須努力爭取 不是用黃金
the afterlife must be earned, not with gold,
而是用善舉 同情心
but by good deeds, compassion,
以及慷慨
and generosity.
我們在人世的所作所為都會被當做參考
What we do, how we act in this life matters.
你在想念她嗎 ?
Are you thinking about her?
你當然在想了
Of course, you are.
你該不會認為我把埃及最偉大的財寶弄丟了吧
You didn't think I'd misplace Egypt's greatest treasure?
你覺得我消失幾天 他們會不會發現 ?
You think they'd miss me if I were gone a few days?
作為國王的主顧問
As chief advisor to the king,
我的職責就是讓他們發現不了
it's my duty to ensure they hardly notice.
但如果有人問到的話...
But if anyone asks...
那就告訴他們我得去幫一位朋友
Tell them I had to go help a friend.
埃及暫時交給你管理了
I leave Egypt in your capable hands.